{"allRoundData":[
	{"name":"Finland0","questionsToShow":10,"pointsAddedForCorrectAnswer":1,"pictureText":"Louhi in the battle for Sampo.","questions":[
		{"questionText":"Why does Louhi want to revenge on Kalevala?","infoText":"Louhi is the leader of Pohjola. Louhi has beautiful daughters whom she marries to men of Kalevala, sadly most of them die. Louhi transforms into an eagle and tries to reclaim Sampo, but it is destroyed in the fight.","answers":[{"answerText":"They stole Sampo","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"They tried to shoot her","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"They were idiots","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What does Louhi transform into?","infoText":"Louhi is the leader of Pohjola. Louhi has beautiful daughters whom she marries to men of Kalevala, sadly most of them die. Louhi transforms into an eagle and tries to reclaim Sampo, but it is destroyed in the fight.","answers":[{"answerText":"A bear","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A crow","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"An eagle","isCorrect":true}]},
		{"questionText":"What are Louhi’s daughters like?","infoText":"Louhi is the leader of Pohjola. Louhi has beautiful daughters whom she marries to men of Kalevala, sadly most of them die. Louhi transforms into an eagle and tries to reclaim Sampo, but it is destroyed in the fight.","answers":[{"answerText":"They are skillful in crafts","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"They are good singers","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"They are beautiful","isCorrect":true}]},
		{"questionText":"Who made the Sampo?","infoText":"The Sampo is a mythical machine forged by Ilmarinen for the Mistress of Pohjola. The Sampo could make flour, salt and gold. It was eventually destroyed in a fight, when Vainamoinen tried to steal it. The Sampo fell into the ocean.","answers":[{"answerText":"Ilmarinen","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Vainamoinen","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Louhi","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What is Vainamoinen´s nickname?","infoText":"Vainamoinen also known as “Steady old Vainamoinen” is the leading figure in many poems of the Kalevala. Vainamoinen is a very skilled singer and does magic with his words. At the end of Kalevala, Vainamoinen is exiled from Kaleva.","answers":[{"answerText":"Old man Vaiski","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Steady old Vainamoinen","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"The ancient mage","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"How was the Sampo destroyed?","infoText":"The Sampo is a mythical machine forged by Ilmarinen for the Mistress of Pohjola. The Sampo could make flour, salt and gold. It was eventually destroyed in a fight, when Vainamoinen tried to steal it. The Sampo fell into the ocean.","answers":[{"answerText":"It was broken in a fight","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"It was stolen by Vainamoinen","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Louhi cooked soup in it","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What is Vainamoinen very skilled at? ","infoText":"Vainamoinen also known as “Steady old Vainamoinen” is the leading figure in many poems of the Kalevala. Vainamoinen is a very skilled singer and does magic with his words. At the end of Kalevala, Vainamoinen is exiled from Kaleva.","answers":[{"answerText":"Singing","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Painting","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Cooking","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Why does Aino drown herself?","infoText":"Aino is a young girl, whom her brother promises in marriage to Vainamoinen to save his own life. Aino refuses to marry old Vainamoinen and drowns herself. Vainamoinen tries to find her but she has transformed into a mermaid.","answers":[{"answerText":"Doesn’t want to marry an old man","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Bad hair day","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Mental problems","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What does Aino transform into?","infoText":"Aino is a young girl, whom her brother promises in marriage to Vainamoinen to save his own life. Aino refuses to marry old Vainamoinen and drowns herself. Vainamoinen tries to find her but she has transformed into a mermaid.","answers":[{"answerText":"A mermaid","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A bear","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"An eagle","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who bakes a rock into Kullervo bread?","infoText":"Untamo kills Kullervo´s  father when Kullervo is very young and he´s forced to serve Untamo. Kullervo is sold to Ilmarinen, whose wife bakes a rock into Kullervo´s bread, which breaks his knife. Kullervo unknowingly seduces his sister and kills himself.","answers":[{"answerText":"Ilmarinen´s wife","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Kullervo´s sister","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Untamo","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who is Kullervo forced to serve?","infoText":"Untamo kills Kullervo´s  father when Kullervo is very young and he´s forced to serve Untamo. Kullervo is sold to Ilmarinen, whose wife bakes a rock into Kullervo´s bread, which breaks his knife. Kullervo unknowingly seduces his sister and kills himself.","answers":[{"answerText":"His uncle Untamo","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"His brother Untamo","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"His father Untamo","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Untamo kills Kullervo´s...?","infoText":"Untamo kills Kullervo´s  father when Kullervo is very young and he´s forced to serve Untamo. Kullervo is sold to Ilmarinen, whose wife bakes a rock into Kullervo´s bread, which breaks his knife. Kullervo unknowingly seduces his sister and kills himself.","answers":[{"answerText":"Father","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Mother","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Sister","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who does Ilmatar give birth to?","infoText":"Ilmatar is the Air Virgin who gives birth to Vainamoinen. A goldeneye lays its eggs on Ilmatar´s knee, and when Ilmatar raises her knee the eggs break and make the world. Ilmatar´s name is also known for healing spells.","answers":[{"answerText":"Vainamöinen","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A goldeneye","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Air Virgin","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Ilmatar´s name is known for healing...?","infoText":"Ilmatar is the Air Virgin who gives birth to Vainamoinen. A goldeneye lays its eggs on Ilmatar´s knee, and when Ilmatar raises her knee the eggs break and make the world. Ilmatar´s name is also known for healing spells.","answers":[{"answerText":"Spells","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Ancient artifacts","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Amulets","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Why was the Sampo important?","infoText":"The Sampo is a mythical machine forged by Ilmarinen for the Mistress of Pohjola. The Sampo could make flour, salt and gold. It was eventually destroyed in a fight, when Vainamoinen tried to steal it. The Sampo fell into the ocean.","answers":[{"answerText":"It had cultural significance","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"It was a family treasure","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"It made its owners rich","isCorrect":true}]}
	]},
	{"name":"Greece1","questionsToShow":10,"pointsAddedForCorrectAnswer":1,"pictureText":"Image of a half-man half-horse creature called centaur.","questions":[
		{"questionText":"What does the phrase “Achilles’ Heel” mean?","infoText":"Achilles, king Peleus’ and Nereid Thetis’ son, is the central hero of Homer’s Iliad. When a baby, his mother held him by the heel and dipped him into river Styx to make him invulnerable. But his heel was left out of the water and, thus, vulnerable. Achilles died from an arrow on that heel.","answers":[{"answerText":"A person’s weak point ","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A person’s strong point","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A person’s wounded heel","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What mythological phrase describes a situation when many bad things happen at the same time?","infoText":"Pandora was the first human woman, created by Greek God Hephaestus under Zeus’ instructions. She opened a jar – given to her as a wedding gift by Zeus - and released all the evils of humanity, such as sickness, death and many others, into the world.","answers":[{"answerText":"Pandora’s Box","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Damocles’ sword","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"The apple of Discord","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What does Zeus, the father of the Olympian gods in Greek Mythology, hold?","infoText":"Zeus, son of Titan Cronus and Titaness Rhea, was the king of all gods of Mount Olympus and father to many heroic and divine children, resulting from his many love affairs. His wife was Hera. He was called The cloud-gatherer and held the thunderbolt.","answers":[{"answerText":"A thunderbolt","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A trident","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A spear","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What is Aphrodite in the Greek Mythology?","infoText":"Aphrodite, the Greek goddess of love and beauty, was born off the coast of Cythera from the foam of the sea (‘aphros’ in Greek). She was married to Hephaestus, the god of blacksmiths and metalworking.","answers":[{"answerText":"The goddess of beauty","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"The goddess of wisdom","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"The goddess of archery","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Where did the Minotaur live, according to Greek Mythology?","infoText":"The Minotaur was a half-man-half-bull monster, son to King Minos’ wife, Pasiphae and Poseidon’s white bull. He lived in a labyrinth in Knossos’ palace, designed by the architect Daedalus and his son, Icarus, on King Minos’ command. He was killed by the Athenian hero, Theseus.","answers":[{"answerText":"In a labyrinth in Crete","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"In the Parthenon in Athens","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"On Olympus mountain","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What kind of creature was Centaur Chiron, who knew Medicine and every art and skill in Greek mythology?","infoText":"Centaur Chiron, son of Titan Cronus and Oceanid Philyra, was a half-man, half-horse creature. He lived in a cave on Mt Pelion, Greece and was very wise. He raised and taught many Greek heroes, such as Achilles, Jason, Hercules and Asclepius.","answers":[{"answerText":"Half man – half horse","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Half man – half lion","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Half man - half snake","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which of the following mythological expressions is used in Computing?","infoText":"The Trojan horse was a trick used by the Greeks. It was a huge, hollow wooden horse given to the Trojans as a present. Hidden in it, Odysseus and other Greek heroes got into Troy and opened the castle gates for the Greek army to enter.","answers":[{"answerText":"Trojan Horse","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Aeolus Bag","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Amaltheia's Horn","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What do people enjoy in the arms of Morpheus?","infoText":"Morpheus, one of the one thousand sons of Sleep, was the god who shaped the dreams of mortals (‘morphi’ in Greek means ‘shape’). Through dreams, he also communicated messages from the gods to people.","answers":[{"answerText":"Sleep","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Drinking","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Dancing","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What was the answer to the riddle of the Sphinx “What creature has got four legs in the morning, two legs at noon and three legs in the evening”?","infoText":"The Sphinx, a mythological creature with a lion’s body, a woman’s head, a reptile’s tail and a bird’s wings, killed passer-by’s who couldn’t solve its riddle. Only Oedipus solved it. The answer was “the man”, because they crawl as babies, walk as grown-ups and use a walking stick when old.","answers":[{"answerText":"The man","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"The bull","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"The horse","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who causes earthquakes according to Greek Mythology?","infoText":"Enceladus, the leader of the Giants, was most probably killed during the Gigantomachy by goddess Athena, who threw Sicily island upon him. Since then he has been struggling to get free, causing earthquakes and the volcanic eruptions of Mt Aetna.","answers":[{"answerText":"Enceladus","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Zeus","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Prometheus","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which beautiful mythological lady travelled with Zeus (in the form of a bull) from Phoenicia to the island of Crete?","infoText":"Zeus fell in love with Europe, a beautiful woman from Phoenicia, when he saw her in a field with her friends. To attract her he turned into a white, lovely bull. Europe caressed him and sat on his back. Immediately Zeus set off, abducting her to Crete where she gave birth to their three sons.","answers":[{"answerText":"Europe","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Asia","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"America","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What was the name of the sea monster that created huge whirlpools and swallowed the ships in the Greek mythology?","infoText":"Charybdis, the daughter of Poseidon and Gaia, was a sea monster that lived on the Asiatic coast of Bosporus, opposite monster Scylla on the European coast. Both appear in Odysseus and the Argonautic expedition myths and are the source of the expression “Between Scylla and Charybdis”, i.e. between two evils.","answers":[{"answerText":"Charybdis","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Lernaean Hydra","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Siren","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"How many were the fates that controlled the thread of life of mortals from birth to death in the Greek mythology?","infoText":"The fates were three: Klotho span the thread of live and symbolized the present, Lachesis symbolized the past and decided what will happen to the mortals and Atropos cut the thread of life, thus, symbolizing the future.","answers":[{"answerText":"Three","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Two","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Four","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What was the disability of Hephaestus, the Greek god of fire?","infoText":"Hephaestus, son of Zeus and Hera, was the Olympian god of fire and metalworking. When a baby, he was cast off Mt Olympus by Hera because he was ugly and deformed. That caused his limping.","answers":[{"answerText":"He limped","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"He was blind","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"He was deaf","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Where in Greece did the Argonauts sail from?","infoText":"The Argonautic expedition was a voyage from ancient Iolcus (Volos,Greece) to Kolchis (Georgia) and involved a group of heroes under the leadership of Jason. The goal was to fetch the Golden Fleece. Recent research has shown that it was a real voyage for gold trade.","answers":[{"answerText":"Iolcus (Greece) to Kolchis (Georgia)","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Thessaloniki (Greece) to Egypt","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Crete to Iolcus (Greece)","isCorrect":false}]}
	]},
	{"name":"Iceland2","questionsToShow":10,"pointsAddedForCorrectAnswer":1,"pictureText":"Yggdrasil the mythical tree that connects the Nine Worlds.","questions":[
		{"questionText":"What is Yggrdrasil and what does it hold?","infoText":"The tree Yggdrasill or ash Yggdrasil is the most secret of all. It has three roots. The first eaches Niflheim, where the well Hvergelmir and the dragon Shock have the roots. The second is in Jotunheimar, there is Mimisbrunnur and the wise giant Mimir. The third is on Heaven, there is Urdurbrunnur.","answers":[{"answerText":"A tree holding nine worlds","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A cup holding the blood of Ymir","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Odin‘s home holding the world together","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What is at the bottom of Yggrdrasil?","infoText":"Urd´s well is a well in Norse mythology. It lies beneath the world tree Yggdrasil, and is associated with a trio of norns (Urdur, Verdandi, and Skuld)","answers":[{"answerText":"Urd´s Well","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Connla´s Well","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Asgard","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which icelandic band wrote a song about the midgard worm?","infoText":"Skálmöld is an Icelandic heavy metal band that was established in 2009. They play a national heavy metal.","answers":[{"answerText":"Skálmöld","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Sárasótt","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Thunder Gods","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who is the god of thunder?","infoText":"Thor, the son of Odin, is the God of Thunder in Norse mythology. He is well-recognized for his hammer which he uses to control the lightning, thunder and storms.","answers":[{"answerText":"Thor","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Odin","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Loki","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What is ragnarok?","infoText":"Ragnarok is a destruction of Valhöll and all life as we know it.","answers":[{"answerText":"Destruction of Valhöll and all life as we know it","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"The sword of Odin","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"The beginning of the world","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What are the names of the three witches that take care of watering the tree Askur Yggdrasil?","infoText":"Urdur, Verdandi and Skuld are three witches in Nordic mythology. They live with Urdarbrunn which stands at one of the three roots of Asks Yggdrasil.","answers":[{"answerText":"Urdur, Verdandi, Skuld","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Karna, Urdur, Frigg","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Skuld, Sigyn, Freyja","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which two gods is Hel the offspring of?","infoText":"Loki is a Norse god of mischief and fatherhood. He is the son of two giants, Fárbauti and Laufey. Anguran was a crater in Jötunheimar, a close friend of Loki. With her he gave birth to his most beautiful offspring: Fenrisulf, Midgardorm and Hel.","answers":[{"answerText":"Loki and Angurboda","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Baldur and Bestla","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Freyja and Freyr","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who was responsible for Baldur´s death?","infoText":"Loki is a Norse god of mischief, as well as fatherhood. He is the son of two giants, Fárbauti and Laufey.","answers":[{"answerText":"Loki","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Odin","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Fenrisúlfur","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What witches lived in the Urðabrunnur?","infoText":"Urdur, Verdandi and Skuld are three witches in Nordic mythology. They live with Urdarbrunn, which stands at one of the three roots of Asks Yggdrasil.","answers":[{"answerText":"Urdur,Verdandi,Skuld","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Idun, Frygg, Freyja","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Skoppa, Skrítla, Skuld","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What is the name of the squirrel who runs up and down Yggdrasill taking insulting messages between the eagle at the top and the serpent at the bottom?","infoText":"Ratatoskur is a squirrel in a Nordic myth that runs up and down the world tree Yggdrasil to carry messages between the eagle perched atop Yggdrasil, and the serpent Níðhöggr.","answers":[{"answerText":"Ratatoskur","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Eagle","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Black Peter","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What is the original norse mythology language?","infoText":"Iceland is an island state in the North Atlantic between Greenland, the Faroe Islands and Norway. Europe's second largest island and the eighteenth largest in the world. About 357,000 people live in Iceland.","answers":[{"answerText":"Icelandic","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Sweedish","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Norwish","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What group name was given to the Norse gods?","infoText":"Aesis are gods of Nordic mythology, one of two categories of gods and the greater. The other party is accustomed to. According to mythology, Asians live in Ásgarður, and those who believe in them are called Asatrites.","answers":[{"answerText":"Aesir","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Falcons","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Heroes","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"How many doors are there in Valhalla?","infoText":"Valhalla is located in Asgard, there are 640 doors. The doors are so wide that through each huge door, 960 warriors can walk side by side.","answers":[{"answerText":"640","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"1680","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"840","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"In Norse mythology, what spirits tended the flowers and trees?","infoText":"Elves are human-shaped supernatural beings. They are some of the most beautiful beings in Norse mythology, more beautiful than the sun. They live in the realm of Alfheim, one of the nine worlds in Norse mythology.","answers":[{"answerText":"Elves","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Yggdrasill","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Midgard","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What are the mortal and godly worlds called respectively?","infoText":"Asgard, one of the Nine Worlds of Norse mythology, is home and fortress of the Aesir, one of the two tribes of gods. The other tribe is Vanir, who live in Vanaheim.  Bifröst, the bridge between the world of men on Earth, Midgard, with the realm of the Aesir, is used for the transport of gods and brave men. The latter will accompany Odin and the other gods in the end-of-time battle of Ragnrok.","answers":[{"answerText":"Asgard and Bifrost","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Midgard and Bifrost","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Midgard and Asgard","isCorrect":false}]}
	]},
	{"name":"Italy3","questionsToShow":10,"pointsAddedForCorrectAnswer":1,"pictureText":"One of the little fairies known as Janas.","questions":[
		{"questionText":"What does The Carnival in Lula represent?","infoText":"Lula Carnival is a metaphorical representation of the death of Dionysus. His death and the shedding of his blood are a symbol of fertility.","answers":[{"answerText":"The death and rebirth of Dyonisus","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"The birth of the king","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"The death of Thor","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What are the Domus de Janas?","infoText":"Domus de Janas are a type of pre-nuragic (from Paleolithic till the Broze age) chamber tombs, resembling houses in their layout, where corpses were buried together with common life objects and walls were decorated with etchings called “petroglifi”.","answers":[{"answerText":"Prenuragic tombs","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Animals shelters","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Houses of elves","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What did the tiny bronze nuragic boats represent?","infoText":"Bronzetti nuragici are small-sized reproductions in bronze of people, utensils, clothes, weapons and animals dating back to the Nuragic age (1500-900 B.C.), which gives us an idea of how society was organized at the time.","answers":[{"answerText":"The boat used to travel","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A toy for children","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"The boat that carried the dead","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Due to old pagan rites linked to water, Sardinia has numerous...?","infoText":"The nuragic holy well is a typical Sardinian bronze age structure for the worship of the waters. Scattered throughout the island, they testify to the deep religiosity of the nuragic population.","answers":[{"answerText":"Sacred wells","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Sacred fountains","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Waterfalls","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What are “bronzetti nuragici”?","infoText":"Bronzetti nuragici are small-sized reproductions in bronze of people, utensils, clothes, weapons and animals dating back to the Nuragic age (1500-900 B.C.), which gives us an idea of how society was organized at the time.","answers":[{"answerText":"Tiny bronze sculptures","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Relics of big vessels","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Skeletons of Protosardinians","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"“Petroglifi” is the name given to which Protosardinian artistic form?","infoText":"Domus de Janas are a type of pre-nuragic (from Paleolithic till the Bronze age) chamber tombs, resembling houses in their layout, where corpses were buried together with common life objects and walls were decorated with etchings called “petroglifi”.","answers":[{"answerText":"Symbolic etchings in old tombs","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Megalithic stones","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Cone-shaped buildings","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What does the thread held by “Sa Filonzana” represent?","infoText":"“Sa Filonzana” was an old woman who held a spindle in her hand and rolled a thin thread which represented life.","answers":[{"answerText":"Life/death","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Happiness/sadness","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Wealth/poverty","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"The masks in Lula’s Carnival have their face covered in...?","infoText":"Lula Carnival is a metaphorical representation of the death of Dionysus. His death and the shedding of his blood are a symbol of fertility.","answers":[{"answerText":"Blood and soot","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Mud","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Bright colors","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who punished children who played in the sun?","infoText":"“Sa Mama e su Sole” was a beautiful but wicked woman  who used to punish all children who went out during the hottest hours in summer, by giving them fever.","answers":[{"answerText":"Sa Mama e su Sole","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Maria Pettenedda","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"The Janas","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"The Sardinian mask of Su Battileddu corresponds to...?","infoText":"Su Battileddu is the sacrificial victim in Lula Carnival and represents the birth and rebirth of Dionysus. He carries horns in his head and his face is covered in blood and soot.","answers":[{"answerText":"The Greek Dionysus","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"The Sardinian Thor","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"The Spanish Jordi","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What are the Janas?","infoText":"According to legends, the janas were tiny winged fairies who lived in holes dug in the rocks, own huge treasures, weaved wonderful clothes and made a light bread. To protect their treasure, they hid the “musca maccedda” (the butcher fly) in treasure chests.","answers":[{"answerText":"Winged fairies","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Wicked witches","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Vestal virgins","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What did Sardinians do in the sacred wells?","infoText":"The nuragic holy well is a typical Sardinian bronze age structure for the worship of the waters. Scattered throughout the island, they testify to the deep religiosity of the nuragic population.","answers":[{"answerText":"Perform water rituals","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Sacrifice lambs","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Sacrifice children","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Where are “nuraghes” located in Sardinia?","infoText":"The Nuraghe is  the main type of ancient megalithic edifice found in Sardinia dating back to the Nuragic age (1500-900 B.C.). More than 7000 nuraghi have been found by archaeologists.","answers":[{"answerText":"All over the island","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"In the north","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"In the south","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What do the typical masks of the Sardinian Carnival represent?","infoText":"Sardinian typical masks are usually a grotesque representation of animals and men connected to the shepherds’ world.","answers":[{"answerText":"Animals","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Ghosts","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Women","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What can be found inside the Domus the Janas?","infoText":"Domus de Janas are a type of pre-nuragic (from Paleolithic till the Broze age) chamber tombs, resembling houses in their layout, where corpses were buried together with common life objects and walls were decorated with etchings called “petroglifi”.","answers":[{"answerText":"Drawings","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A deep well","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Furniture","isCorrect":false}]}
	]},
	{"name":"Latvia4","questionsToShow":10,"pointsAddedForCorrectAnswer":1,"pictureText":"Lacplesis the bear slayer.","questions":[
		{"questionText":"What does the lime tree symbolize in Latvian mythology?","infoText":"Lime tree is very famous in Latvian mythology. In Latvia we have lime tree alleys and lime tree blossom is used for making teas, it cures illnesses.","answers":[{"answerText":"Woman’s strength","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Woman’s beauty","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Woman’s intelligence","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What does the expression: “The morning hour has gold in its mouth” mean?","infoText":"The earlier you get up the more you can manage and the result is the best.","answers":[{"answerText":"It’s the most productive","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Breakfast is very essential","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Do your morning prayer","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Why does Latvian epic hero Lacplesis have his strength in his ears?","infoText":"Lacplesis (The Bear Slayer} was chosen by the gods to become a hero of his people.","answers":[{"answerText":"To hear his nation","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"To hear his enemies","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"He has magic earrings","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What are the names of Gods of Destiny in Latvian mythology?","infoText":"In Latvian mythology we have 3 different gods of destiny.","answers":[{"answerText":"Laima, Dekla, Karta","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Anita, Saule, Mara","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Liga, Janis, Hugo","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"In which summer month do Latvians have a holiday “Ligo” when they eat cheese, make a fire and dance around it?","infoText":"Ligo Night is celebrated on the 23rd of June and it is called also Summer Solstice.","answers":[{"answerText":"June","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"July","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"August","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What is the meaning of the sign of fire?","infoText":"In Latvian mythology we have many signs and each one of them has a different meaning.","answers":[{"answerText":"It gives energy","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"It protects from evil powers","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"It strengthens your health","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"How will you finish the saying “When you can hear a clear echo from the forest, then...?”","infoText":"It was and still is popular to predict the weather looking at different signs in nature.","answers":[{"answerText":"Weather will be good","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"It will start raining","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Weather will be cold","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What does the sign of Sun look like in Latvian mythology?","infoText":"Sun is one of the oldest Gods in Latvian mythology.","answers":[{"answerText":"Like a circle","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Like a triangle","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Like a star","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"To which God in Latvian mythology do these items belong: a sword, a whip, an iron whip?","infoText":"In Latvian mythology every God has his own tools, which symbolize them.","answers":[{"answerText":"Perkons (Thunder)","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Jumis","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Usins","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What did the God Usins protect in Latvian mythology?","infoText":"The God Usins is the symbol of light and spring.","answers":[{"answerText":"Horses and bees","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":" Workers and work","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":" Water creatures","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Why can’t you wash yourself in a bathhouse on the day before Easter (because it means...)?","infoText":"Many beliefs in Latvian mythology are connected with forces above human power. They are often mentioned in different occasions. Going to a bath house is very important in Latvian culture due to its power to cure health problems.","answers":[{"answerText":"Washing in Christ's blood","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"You reject health","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"It is pointless","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which of the following poisonous plants are very healthy if made properly?","infoText":"In Latvian mythology are mentioned medicaments made from the most unconventional plants and even animal organs, such as celandine, beaver’s testis and more.","answers":[{"answerText":"Death cup","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Hogweed","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Poisonous yew","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which God in Latvian mythology is called the God of Dawn?","infoText":"Many gods in Latvian mythology symbolize the nature. Dawn is very important in Latvians’ life as a new day starts. Auseklis- means a morning star.","answers":[{"answerText":"Auseklis","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Thunder","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Sun","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"How many dishes do Latvians have to eat for festive dinner on Winter Solstice to have a rich next year?","infoText":"Latvians have a lot of traditions for celebrating Winter Solstice like decorating the house, singing songs and having a meal together.","answers":[{"answerText":"9","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"6","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"12","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What was the purpose of eating grey peas and beans on Winter Solstice?","infoText":"If you eat peas or beans you will not have a reason for crying the following year.","answers":[{"answerText":"You will not cry","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Will have good harvest","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"You will be rich","isCorrect":false}]}
	]},
	{"name":"Poland5","questionsToShow":10,"pointsAddedForCorrectAnswer":1,"pictureText":"Nyja the god of the underworld.","questions":[
		{"questionText":"According to the Legend of Brave Giewont, what was Dragon’s son’s name who wanted to become a musician?","infoText":"There was a dragon which changed into a human and had a lot of children who were given special gifts by their father. One of his sons was Giewont - a powerful knight and one of the highest Polish summit.","answers":[{"answerText":"Garluch","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Harwan","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Magura","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"According to the Legend of Brave Giewont, what did Dragon change into for its beloved Magura?","infoText":"There was a dragon which changed into a human and had a lot of children who were given special gifts by their father. One of his sons was Giewont - a powerful knight and one of the highest Polish summit.","answers":[{"answerText":"A human","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A horse","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A sea creature","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What was Obosita, according to the Legend of Brave Giewont?","infoText":"There was a dragon which changed into a human and had a lot of children who were given special gifts by their father. One of his sons was Giewont -  a powerful knight and one of the highest Polish summit.","answers":[{"answerText":"Dragon’s youngest daughter","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Giewont’s wife","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Frost’s lover","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"According to the Legend of Brave Giewont, what did Muran want to be?","infoText":"There was a dragon which changed into a human and had a lot of children who were given special gifts by their father. One of his sons was Giewont - a powerful knight and one of the highest Polish summit.","answers":[{"answerText":"A builder","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A shepherd","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A knight","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"According to The Legend of Brave Giewont, who tried to kidnap Dragon and Magura’s daughter?","infoText":"There was a dragon which changed into a human and had a lot of children who were given special gifts by their father. One of his sons was Giewont - a powerful knight and one of the highest Polish summit.","answers":[{"answerText":"Frost","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Giewont","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Harwan","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"According to the legend of Creation of the Vistula River, the king and father of two daughters Bialka and Czarnocha was the king of which mountain range?","infoText":"The Creation of the Vistula River is a legend that tells the story how the king of mountain range Beskid and the father of two daughters – Bialka and Czarnocha created the main river in Poland. (the Vistula).","answers":[{"answerText":"Beskid","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Harwan","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Czarnocha","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What does the coat of arms of Warsaw consists of?","infoText":"The coat of arms of Warsaw consists of a syrenka (little mermaid) in a red field. The syrenka has traditionally held a silver sword although this does not appear on more recent versions.","answers":[{"answerText":"A mermaid in a red field","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A fish in a red field","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"An eagle in a red field","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who is the legendary ancestor of Poland?","infoText":"The legend states that three brothers, on a hunting trip, followed different prey and thus travelled (and settled, founding three Slavic people: the Poles, the Czechs and the Rus’) in different directions: Lech (north), Czech (west) and Rus (east).","answers":[{"answerText":"Lech","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Rus","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Czech","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who is the Goddess of love, the protector of families and guardian of the house of human in Slavic Mythology?","infoText":"The Goddess of love, the protector of families and guardian of the house of human. Along with Marzanna and Dziewanna she is believed to be the most important emanation of Mighty Mother and Mother Nature.","answers":[{"answerText":"Lada – Lela","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Marzanna","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Dziewanna","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Kuj – Kowal was a Slavic God of the Sun and heavenly fire as well as a heavenly blacksmith, the creator of astronomical, celestial objects. What was his attribute?","infoText":"Slavic God of the Sun and heavenly fire as well as a heavenly blacksmith, the creator of astronomical, celestial objects. He was also the guardian of craftsmen. It is believed that he forged the sun with his fiery hammer and placed it on the vault of heaven.","answers":[{"answerText":"Lightning","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A sword","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A black horse","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which town was the first capital of Poland?","infoText":"The legend states that three brothers, on a hunting trip, followed different prey and thus travelled (and settled, founding three Slavic people: the Poles, the Czechs and the Rus’) in different directions: Lech (north), Czech (west) and Rus (east).","answers":[{"answerText":"Gniezno","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Crawcow","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Warsaw","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who was Pawel Wasznik?","infoText":"Pawel Wasznik is a legendary local hero who helped Polish knights seized the Drahim castle from the Templars.","answers":[{"answerText":"A fisherman","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A Templar","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A monk","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"How did Pawel Wasznik help Polish knights to free the Drahim castle?","infoText":"Pawel Wasznik is a legendary local hero who helped Polish knights seized the Drahim castle from the Templars.","answers":[{"answerText":"By using fishing nets","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"By opening the gate","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"By burning the castle","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What was Wars respected as by the people of his settlement (according to the legend of Wars and Sawa)?","infoText":"The legend of Wars and Sawa explains the origins of the name of the current capital of Poland Warsaw.","answers":[{"answerText":"Hardworking and kind","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"The best ruler","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"The bravest knight","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What helped Sawa, according to The Legend of Wars and Sawa, to change into the woman?","infoText":"The legend of Wars and Sawa explains the origins of the name of the current capital of Poland Warsaw.","answers":[{"answerText":"An amorous kiss","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A spell","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A magical potion","isCorrect":false}]}
	]},
	{"name":"Spain6","questionsToShow":10,"pointsAddedForCorrectAnswer":1,"pictureText":"Saint George fighting the dragon.","questions":[
		{"questionText":"What is the Salt Grinder’s moral legend?","infoText":"The selfish brother took it and told the grinder to create salt while he was in his ship, but he didn't know the magic words to stop it, so there was too much salt that the ship sank. The magic grinder is still making salt, and that's why the sea water is salty.","answers":[{"answerText":"Not to be selfish","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Not to be dishonest","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Not to be greedy","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"From where was the drummer of Bruc Mountain?","infoText":"A long time ago, when a group of French soldiers wanted to attack the Montserrat mountains, one boy from San Pedor defended these playing his drum.","answers":[{"answerText":"San Pedor","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Monestrol","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Manresa","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Where can you visit a monument after the drummer of Bruc mountain?","infoText":"Now we can see the monument of this hero in the magic mountains of Montserrat.","answers":[{"answerText":"In Monserrat","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"In Bruc’s village","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"In San Pedor","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"According to the legend where did the Marfantos live?","infoText":"The legend tells that in the Middle Ages there were some gallery ships in Ebro delta, which kept prisoners who were enemies of the Kingdom of Catalonia and Aragon.","answers":[{"answerText":"Ebro Delta","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Llobregat Delta","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Francolí river","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"According to legend, which was the Marfantos appearance?","infoText":"The  convicts received the malefic effects of the stars and released their spirits out of their bodies. Some of them became evil ghosts and some others began to eat up one to another. The next morning, nothing.","answers":[{"answerText":"A kind of giants","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A kind of elves","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A kind of mummies","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What is the name of the village where Saint George’s legend was based of?","infoText":"Saint George's story is a set in Montblanc, Catalonia. The legend is about an evil dragon which ate people.","answers":[{"answerText":"Montblanc","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Vic","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Barcelona","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who accepted the king to include it in the raffle?","infoText":"They decided every week who was gonna be eaten by the dragon with a ruffle. One day the princess was chosen so she had to go. When she was going to die a handsome knight appeared and saved the princess killing the dragon.","answers":[{"answerText":"The princess","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"The servant","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"His wife","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Where does the rose appear in Saint Georges’ Legend?","infoText":"From the blood of the dragon a beautiful red rose emerged and the knight gave it to the princess.","answers":[{"answerText":"From the dragon’s blood","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"From Saint George’s blood","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"From a well","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who was trying to attack Montserrat in The Timbaler del Bruc myth?","infoText":"A long time ago , when a group of Napoleon’s soldiers wanted to attack the Montserrat mountains, one boy from San Pedor defended these playing his drum.","answers":[{"answerText":"The French Army","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"The Italian Army","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"The British Army","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What did the Timbaler del Bruc used to defend Montserrat from the attackers in The Timbaler del Bruc myth?","infoText":"The timbaler del Bruc defeated the army by playing on his instrument.","answers":[{"answerText":"The drums’ sound","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Some soldiers","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A gun","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which creature had the villagers of Banyoles terrified?","infoText":"A beast of terrible dimensions had found shelter in a deep cavern on the shores of Lake Banyoles, in Gerona. It is described as having a thick skin of scales provided with sharp spines on the spine and with large wings.","answers":[{"answerText":"A water dragon","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A Centaur","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A terrible racoon","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which myth could be related to the Banyoles myth?","infoText":"According to the legend, the Banyoles monster lives in the Banyoles Lake in Girona of northern eastern Spain hundreds years of ago.","answers":[{"answerText":"The Loch Ness monster","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"The Boe legend","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"The minotaur’s myth","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which was the power of the Banyoles Monster?","infoText":"They say that he spit fire through his eyes and that his breath was so foul that he could poison the water, dry the fields and transmit diseases to animals and people.","answers":[{"answerText":"It could spit fire","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"It could fly","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"It could teleport","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Why did people become ill when they saw Pyrene?","infoText":"Olympus reigned over the face of the earth and had a beautiful daughter called Pyrene. She was so supremely beautiful, that many people fell ill with love to see her.","answers":[{"answerText":"She was really beautiful","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"She cast a curse upon people","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"She had poisonous eyes","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What is the most important feeling in Pyrene’s legend?","infoText":"When Pyrene was about to die Hercules declared his Eternal love before she passed away. Hercules buried his love, placing huge stones on her body. He came to erect enormous mountains of stone, which today are the Pyrenees.","answers":[{"answerText":"Love","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Freedom","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Revenge","isCorrect":false}]}
	]},
	{"name":"FinalRound7","questionsToShow":15,"pointsAddedForCorrectAnswer":1,"pictureText":"empty","questions":[
		{"questionText":"Where does Louhi rule?","infoText":"Louhi is the leader of Pohjola. Louhi has beautiful daughters whom she marries to men of Kalevala, sadly most of them die. Louhi transforms into an eagle and tries to reclaim Sampo, but it is destroyed in the fight.","answers":[{"answerText":"Pohjola","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Kalevala","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A mushroom forest","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Middle Earth","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who proposes to Aino?","infoText":"Aino is a young girl, whom her brother promises in marriage to Vainamoinen to save his own life. Aino refuses to marry old Vainamoinen and drowns herself. Vainamoinen tries to find her but she has transformed into a mermaid.","answers":[{"answerText":"Vainamoinen","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Joukahainen","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Antero Vipunen","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Sampo","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Kullervo kills himself because?","infoText":"Untamo kills Kullervo´s  father when Kullervo is very young and he´s forced to serve Untamo. Kullervo is sold to Ilmarinen, whose wife bakes a rock into Kullervo´s bread, which breaks his knife. Kullervo unknowingly seduces his sister and kills himself.","answers":[{"answerText":"He seduces his sister","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"His father´s knife broke","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"His father is killed","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Nobody understands him","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"How is the world made according to Kalevala?","infoText":"Ilmatar is the Air Virgin who gives birth to Vainamoinen. A goldeneye lays its eggs on Ilmatar´s knee, and when Ilmatar raises her knee the eggs break and make the world. Ilmatar´s name is also known for healing spells.","answers":[{"answerText":"A goldenyey lays its eggs on Ilmatar´s knee and they break","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"A goldeneye dies","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A goldeneye lays its eggs and they hatch","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Ilmatar burns in a fire","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Where is Vainamoinen exiled from?","infoText":"Vainamoinen also known as “Steady old Vainamoinen” is the leading figure in many poems of the Kalevala. Vainamoinen is a very skilled singer and does magic with his words. At the end of Kalevala, Vainamoinen is exiled from Kaleva.","answers":[{"answerText":"Russia","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Tuonela","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Turku","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Kalevala","isCorrect":true}]},
		{"questionText":"Who was the leader of the Argonautic expedition?","infoText":"The Argonautic expedition was a voyage from ancient Iolcus (Volos,Greece) to Kolchis (Georgia) and involved a group of heroes under the leadership of Jason. The goal was to fetch the Golden Fleece. Recent research has shown that it was a real voyage for gold trade.","answers":[{"answerText":"Jason","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Hercules","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Menelaus","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Poseidon","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What did Pythia do after she chewed laurel leaves in Delphi (Greece)?","infoText":"Pythia was the high priestess and the oracle of the Temple of Apollo in Delphi. She sat on a tripod in ecstasy, due to the gases of burning laurel leaves and methane, and communicated the god’s oracle to the people in a laconic and ambiguous way.","answers":[{"answerText":"She gave oracles","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"She danced in ecstasy","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"She cured with herbs","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"She worshipped Apollo god","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What happened to people who looked at Medusa?","infoText":"In the Greek Mythology Medusa was one of the three gorgons. She was a winged female monster with living venomous snakes instead of hair. Whoever looked at her eyes got petrified. She was killed by Perseus with the help of goddess Athena.","answers":[{"answerText":"They got petrified","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"They became a monster","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"They got wiser","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"They forgot everything","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which war did the Apple of Discord lead to?","infoText":"At the wedding of Peleus and Thetis, Eris, the goddess of dispute, tossed a golden apple to be taken by the most beautiful woman. Hera, Athena and Aphrodite were fighting for it until Paris gave it to Aphrodite, who had promised him beautiful Helen as his wife. But she was Menelaus’ wife so when Paris took her, the Trojan War broke out.","answers":[{"answerText":"Trojan War","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Titanomachy","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Gigantomachy","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Lapiths and Centaurs battle","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which was NOT a Hercules’ labour?","infoText":"Hercules, the son of Greek god Zeus and the mortal woman Alcmene, was famous for his strength and for his 12 labours. When he was a new-born baby, he killed the two serpents that goddess Hera had sent to kill him.","answers":[{"answerText":"Killing the Minotaur","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Killing the Lernaean Hydra","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Cleaning the Augean stables","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Killing the Stymphalian birds","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who is Loki’s father?","infoText":"Odin is the greatest of gods in Nordic mythology. He is a god of wisdom, poetry, war, death, divination and magic. Son of Bor and the giantess (jötunn) Bestla. He created Heaven, Earth, Ash and Embla.","answers":[{"answerText":"Odin","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Thor","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Axla Björn","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Mímir","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What sort of tree is Yggdrasill, the world-tree?","infoText":"Ash trees are medium to large trees of the genus Fraxinus. They grow in most parts of the world.","answers":[{"answerText":"Ask (Ash Tree))","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Oak","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Elder","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Larch","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"In Norse mythology, what was the name for the city of the giants?","infoText":"That is one of the nine worlds in Norse Mythology. The others are called Niflheim, Muspelheim, Asgard, Midgard, Vanaheim, Alfheim, Svartalfheim, Helheim. Jotunheimar is the homeland of the giants.","answers":[{"answerText":"Jotunheim","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Ásgardur","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Urdarbrunnur","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Niflheimar","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What is the name of the dragon that gnaws at the roots of the ash?","infoText":"In Norse mythology, Níðhöggr is a dragon who gnaws at a root of the world tree, Yggdrasil.","answers":[{"answerText":"Nídhöggur","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Sirius","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Moraga","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Dragon King","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What name is given to the home of the gods in Norse mythology?","infoText":"Ásgardur is one of the Nine Worlds and home to the Aesir of gods. Odin and his wife, Frigg, are the rulers of Asgard.","answers":[{"answerText":"Ásgardur","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Gladheimar","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Urdarbrunnur","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Niflheimar","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which one of Odin‘s sons owns the horn Gjallarhorn?","infoText":"In Norse mythology, Heimdallr is a god who possesses the resounding horn Gjallarhorn, owns the golden-maned horse Gulltoppr, is called the shining god and is the son of Nine Mothers.","answers":[{"answerText":"Heimdallur","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Loki","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Thor","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Týr","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Approximately how many “nuraghi” are there in Sardinia?","infoText":"The Nuraghe is the main type of ancient megalithic edifice found in Sardinia dating back to the Nuragic age (1500-900 B.C.).More than 7000 nuraghi have been found by archaeologists.","answers":[{"answerText":"7000","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"2000","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"1000","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"10000","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What’s the name of Lula’s typical mask?","infoText":"Su Battileddu is the sacrificial victim in Lula Carnival and represents the birth and rebirth of Dionysus. He carries horns in his head and his face is covered in blood and soot.","answers":[{"answerText":"Battileddu","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Issohadore","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Mamuthone","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Merdule","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What is “S’Accabbadora” used to?","infoText":"“S’Accabbadora” was a woman who was called to put an end to the agony of old dying people.","answers":[{"answerText":"Kill sick people","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Celebrate weddings","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Scare children","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Baptize children","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What are the nuraghes?","infoText":"The Nuraghe is  the main type of ancient megalithic edifice found in Sardinia dating back to the Nuragic age (1500-900 B.C.). More than 7000 nuraghi have been found by archaeologists.","answers":[{"answerText":"Old Sardinian dwellings or fortresses","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Old Sardinian schools","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Old Sardinian temples","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Sardinian hotels","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What did “Sa Musca Maccedda” do to people?","infoText":"The muscas macceddas (butcher flies) were horrible insects with goat’s head, one eye, sharp teeth, short wings and a tail with a poisonous sting. They protected the janas and their treasure chests.","answers":[{"answerText":"Guarded the janas’ treasure","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Protected children at night","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Stole jewels","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Attacked them in the street","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What does the oak tree symbolize in Latvian mythology?","infoText":"Oak is a very significant tree in Latvian mythology and nowadays Latvians plant this tree at their homes, fathers plant this tree for their sons.","answers":[{"answerText":"Male strength","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Human health","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Youth","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Female beauty","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What is the main subject in Latvian mythology?","infoText":"Latvians have always been very close to nature, caring about plants and animals. They have numerous folk songs about nature.","answers":[{"answerText":"Nature","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Food","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Inner peace","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Work","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Why was the River Gauja, according to Latvian mythology, created so winding?","infoText":"There are many tales about geographical phenomena in Latvian mythology which tell about the origin of rivers, lakes, rocks. A fox was trying to escape the flowing water and the river was chasing it.","answers":[{"answerText":"The river was following a fox","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"There was an earthquake","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"To protect from invaders","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"The river met mountains on way","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What does a mythological belief say about washing your face with dew in the morning of Summer Solstice?","infoText":"There are many folksongs telling that you don’t sleep on that night, you wait for the sunrise and wash you face with dew.","answers":[{"answerText":"You will be beautiful","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"You will be lucky","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"You will get healthy","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"You will be rich","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which of the Latvian Goddesses is Mother of Earth?","infoText":"Each of the Latvian Gods has its particular power. Many Goddesses are called Mothers.","answers":[{"answerText":"Mara","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Sun","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Laima","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Jumis","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"How was the dragon which lived near Krakow killed?","infoText":"The legend of King Krak is about the creation of one of the biggest and oldest Polish town Krakow, which is situated at the Vistula river.","answers":[{"answerText":"By a humble shoemaker","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"With poisoned fish","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"By an archer","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"By a brave knight","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What was the attribute of the Goddess of youth Dziewanna?","infoText":"The Goddess of youth, spring, animals, hunting and wild nature. She was taking care of woods, groves and healing all the inhabitants of woods and groves.","answers":[{"answerText":"A bow","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"An apple","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A horse","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"A swan","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who was the God of Heaven and the bolts?","infoText":"The God of Heaven and the bolts overlord, also the highest overlord of fate and fortune so he was the causer of both successful and inauspicious events. Roaming around the world, he was giving people all the goods they needed.","answers":[{"answerText":"Jasz","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Nyja","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Lado ","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Lel","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Where did Lech found his borough, according to the legend of Lech, Czech and Rus, Lech (legendary ancestor of Polish nation)?","infoText":"The legend states that three brothers, on a hunting trip, followed different prey and thus travelled (and settled, founding three Slavic people: the Poles, the Czechs and the Rus’) in different directions: Lech (north), Czech (west) and Rus (east).","answers":[{"answerText":"On the fertile lands","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"In the tall mountains","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"On vast fertile plains","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"In the desert","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Who was supposed to join all the tribes together, according to the Legend of King Krak?","infoText":"The legend of King Krak is about the creation of one of the biggest and oldest Polish town Krakow, which is situated at the Vistula river.","answers":[{"answerText":"Krak","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Lech","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Scuba","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Zaganna","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What physical appearance do Minairons have?","infoText":"Minairons are small creatures born from the Menaironera herb which blooms and grazes in the summer solstice. It grows in deep caves kept by giants and dragons that only let Minairons leave the cave at the midnight of Saint John’s.","answers":[{"answerText":"Green coloured small creatures","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Green coloured big beasts","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Red creatures as big as a human","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"People with green eyes","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Where are Minairons kept?","infoText":"The legend says that Minairons are kept in the recipient where we keep needles, only in the ones which are from a recognized farmhouse in the villages where the legend is from.","answers":[{"answerText":"In an unknown plant","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"In a cave","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"In the mountain","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"In a needles recipient","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What are the names of the wolves in Pratdip’s Legend?","infoText":"The myth says that in the woods near the town called Pratdip, there are some wolves called Dips who are the devil’s messengers.","answers":[{"answerText":"Dips","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Wolfies","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Dogs","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Foxes","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"Which was the food that nourished the wolves in Pratdip’s Legend?","infoText":"They are big and black hounds, and blood nourishes them. At night, the Dips leave the forest to devour the cattle and the drunk people who are out.","answers":[{"answerText":"Human blood","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"Rice and vegetables","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"People’s flesh","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"Burgers and French fries","isCorrect":false}]},
		{"questionText":"What did the main character of the Salt Grinder did for a living?","infoText":"Once upon a time there were two brothers. One was a poor fisherman and the other was a rich and avaricious person who never helped his brother. One day, an ancient woman gave a magic grinder to the fisherman which made wishes come true.","answers":[{"answerText":"He was a fisherman","isCorrect":true},{"answerText":"He was a priest","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"He was a hunter","isCorrect":false},{"answerText":"He was a writer","isCorrect":false}]}
	]}
]}